(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-04T09:14:32.960686",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
沙花叉クロヱ 卒業ライブ
Sakamata Chloe Graduation Live
開け放たれた この部屋には誰もいない
There's no one left in this opened room,
潮風の匂い 浸みついた椅子がひとつ
just a single chair that smells of the sea breeze.
あなたが迷わないように 空けておくよ
I'll leave it open for you, so you won't lose your way.
軋む戸を叩いて
As the door makes a creaking sound.
なにかしら話せばいいのかしら
What should I say when I knock on it?
星が降る夜に あなたにあえた
あの夜を忘れはしない
On a night of shooting stars, I met you.
I'll never forget that night.
大切なことは 言葉にならない
夏の日に起きた全て
The most important things never make it into words,
of everything that happened on that summer day.
思いがけず光るのは 海の幽霊
Out of the blue, they glitter: The spirits of the sea.
風薫る 砂浜で また会いましょう
On a beach graced by the fresh summer breeze,
let us meet again.
パレ、パレ、パレ、輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright!
呼び合う声を 合図に
Taking our calling voices as the signal,
パレ、パレ、パレ、探しにゆく
Parade, parade, parade! We go searching,
スタートは 何度だって
no matter how many times we start anew.
みんな 今日は沙花叉の卒業ライブに来てくれて本当にありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to Sakamata's graduation live today!
頑張り、頑張りますので、応援よろしくお願いします！
I'll do my absolute best, so please give me your support!
ただ 独り言をつぶった
I simply muttered to myself alone,
ただ 始まりたくて走った
running simply because I wanted it to begin.
遠く 暗がりでにともった
Far away, a light flickered in the darkness.
それは まぶしすぎた名前
That was a name that shone far too bright.
それは 優しすぎる思い出もっと
That was a memory far too gentle, always...
近づけと 手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer.
思いがけず 結び合った
Unexpectedly, our paths intertwined.
ほら 今
Look, now...
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ 呼び合う声を 合図に
It's time to shine, taking our cue from voices calling out!
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しにいくの スタートは 何度だって
Let's go search for it, however many times we start over.
ただ 独り言を紡いだ
I just wove together lonely words,
ただ 始まりたくて走った
I just ran because I wanted to begin.
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Far away, a light flickered in the darkness—
それは 眩し過ぎた 名前
a name that shone too brightly.
それは 優し過ぎる 思い出 もっと
And memories far too gentle, even more so.
近づけと 手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand, wishing to get closer.
思いがけず 結び合った
Unexpectedly, our bonds tied together.
ほら 今
Look, now,
迷子は "僕等" になった
the lost ones have become "us."
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
It's time to shine!
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your love along with you.
風、夢、羽
Wind, dreams, feathers,
飛び立てるさ
let's take flight!
ささやかな祈りは 光
Gentle prayers are our light,
終わりなき兆し
an endless omen.
君を 見つけたこと
Finding you
胸を 張れるよ
is something I can be proud of.
ここから
From here,
これから
from now on,
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を
Singing of uncertain feelings
歌おう 恥ずかしかなんて ないよ
without feeling any shame.
誰も 解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary world no one can decode,
いつか また 逢える おまじない
a spell so we can meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
A story that started from zero that day,
数え切れない 言の葉
with countless words,
数えるような 想いじゃないさ
not feelings that can just be counted.
ほら 今
Look, now,
"僕等" を
let's call "us"
一つと 呼ぼう
as one.
Parade, Parade, Parade!
美しいんだよ
It's all so beautiful!
許し合える 刹那 夜は きらめく
Moments of forgiveness twinkling in the night.
雨、晴れ、カレイド
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope,
またとない空
a once-in-a-lifetime sky.
相応しい 旅路とは
A journey fitting for us
君と 有ることさ
is being right here by your side.
君と 有ることなんだ
Yes, being right here by your side.
"ただいま" を 聞けば
When you say "I'm home",
"おかえり" って 叫ぶ よ
we shout "Welcome back!" in return.
当たり前 じゃ ない か
Isn't that how it should be?
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
It's time to shine!
暗がりを 満たす の は
What fills the darkness
君 だ ぼく だ !
is you and me!
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
It's time to shine!
暗がりを 満たす の は
What fills the darkness
君だ 僕だ
is you and me!
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
It's time to shine!
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your love along with you.
風、夢、羽
Wind, dreams, feathers,
飛び立てるさ
let's take flight!
ささやかな祈りは 光
Gentle prayers are our light,
終わりなき兆し
an endless omen.
君と 飛び込んでゆく
Diving in with you
素敵なスタートさ
to a wonderful start.
ここから
From here,
これから
from now on,
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
あのバンドの歌が私には かん高く響く 笑い声に聴こえる
That band's songs sound to me like shrill laughter.
あのバンドの歌が私には 穿つ踏切の音みたい
That band's songs are to me like the piercing clang of a railway crossing.
背中を押すな
Don't push me forward,
もうそこに列車が来る
there's a train coming right there.
背中を押すな おすすめよ
Don't push me forward, it's recommended.
目を閉じる
I close my eyes;
暗闇に差す後光
a halo in the darkness.
耳塞ぐ
I cover my ears;
確実に刻む鼓動
a steady beating pulse.
胸の奥 身を揺す振る心臓
Deep in my chest, my heart makes my body sway.
他に何も聴きたくない 私が放つ音以外
I don't want to hear anything else, nothing but the sounds I'm making.
不協和音に居場所を探した 悲しい歌に救われていたんだけど
Looking for a place to belong in the dissonance, I was saved by a sad song,
あのバンドの歌が誰かにはギフトで 私だけが間違いばかりみたい
but that band's song is a gift to someone else, while I feel like I'm the only one making mistakes.
That band's song is a gift to someone else, while I feel like I'm the only one making mistakes.
私 だらけの間違いばかりみたい
Surrounded by nothing but my own mistakes...
目を閉じる
I close my eyes;
暗闇に差す後光
a halo in the darkness.
耳塞ぐ
I cover my ears;
確実に刻む鼓動
a steady beating pulse.
胸の奥 身を揺す振る心臓
Deep in my chest, my heart makes my body sway.
あのバンドの歌が私には
That band's songs sound to me
かん高い響く笑い声に聞こえる
like shrill laughter all around.
あのバンドの歌が私には
That band's songs are to me
つんざく踏切の音みたい
like the piercing clang of a railway crossing.
背中を押すなよ
Don't push me forward,
もうそこに列車が来る
there's a train coming.
目を気ばる
I close my eyes;
暗い闇に差す後光
there's a halo in the darkness.
耳を塞ぐ
I cover my ears;
確かに刻む鼓動
there's a steady beating pulse within.
胸の奥 身を揺らす心臓
Deep in my chest, my heart makes my body sway.
他に何も聴きたくない
I don't want to hear anything else,
私が放つ音以外
nothing but the sounds I'm making.
背中を押し合おうよ
I close my eyes;
おすなよ
there's a halo in the darkness.
たやすく触るなよ
I cover my ears...
出発のベルが鳴る
the departure bell rings.
乗客は私一人だけ
I'm the only passenger.
手を叩く 私だけの音
The sound of clapping, sounds for me alone.
足鳴らす 足跡の残すまで
Feet stomping until tracks are left behind.
目を開ける 孤独の称号
I opened my eyes as a loner
受け入れる 高貴の衝動
and accepted it, moving forward.
今胸の奥 確かめる心音
Right now, deep inside, my heart tells me...
他に何も聴きたくない
I don't want to hear anything else,
私が放つ音以外
nothing but the sounds I'm making.
いらない
I don't need anything else.
背中を押すなよ
Don't push me forward,
たやすい心触るなよ
don't touch my heart so frivolously.
出発のベルが鳴る
The departure bell rings.
乗客は私一人だけ
I'm the only passenger.
手を叩く 私だけの音
The sound of clapping, sounds for me alone.
足鳴らす 足跡の残すまで
Feet stomping until tracks are left behind.
目を開ける 孤独の称号
I opened my eyes as a loner
受け入れる 高貴の衝動
and accepted it, moving forward.
今胸の奥 確かめる心音
Right now, deep inside, my heart tells me...
他に何も聴きたくない
I don't want to hear anything else,
私が放つ音以外
nothing but the sounds I'm making.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration
人を過度に信じないように
I do the things I do
愛さないように期待しないように
so I won't be trusting, and so I won't be loving.
とか言って角が立たないように
I'll never hope for anything.
気取らないように目立たないように
Even then, I'll go along, acting very carefully.
誰一人傷付けぬように
Ego never growing.
虐めぬように殺さぬように
I do the things I do
とか言って偽善がバレないように
so I won't be hurting, and so I'm not a bully.
威張らないように
I won't give in to murdering.
軽いジョークやリップサービスも忘れないように
Even then, I'll go along, faking almost everything.
どんな時も笑って愛嬌振りまくように
So I don't act arrogantly,
ビターチョコデコレーション
I'll say a joke or two.
兎角言わずにたント召し上がれ
Bitter choco decoration,
ビターチョコデコレーション
be sure to eat it 'til it's gone.
食わず嫌いはちゃんと直さなきゃ
Bitter choco decoration,
頭空っぽその後に残る心が本物なら
a picky eater through and through.
きっと君だって同じ事
Empty out your mind and then you'll realize.
「ところで一つ伺いますが
If your heart is real...
先日何処かで？…やっぱりいいや」
when you cast it aside, surely you're the same.
無駄に自我を晒さぬように
I do the things I do
話さないように分からないように
so I won't expose me and so you'll never know me.
でも絶対口を閉ざさぬように
You won't be getting close to me.
笑うより笑われるように
Even then, I'll go along, always speaking freely.
人をちゃんと敬うように
I make them laugh so easy,
崇めるように讃えるように
instead of making fun of me.
でも決して嫌味にならないように
I do the things I do, coming off politely.
ふざけないように
I praise them very highly.
集団参加の終身刑
Administer all their qualities.
またへーこらへーこら言っちゃってさ
Even then, I'll go along, never speaking bitterly.
「あれっ前髪ちょーぜつさいきょーじゃん！」
So I don't act ignorantly.
とかどーでもいーのに言っちゃってさ
Prison bound, we participate.
毎朝毎晩もう限界
Here I go, yet again.
宗教的社会の集団リンチ
Saying "What? No way!"
でも決して発狂しないように
"I'm in awe 'cause your bangs, yeah they're all the craze!"
ビターチョコデコレーション
Even though, what i see, yeah, it's all the same.
時に孤独な愛は君を汚す
Morning or night, I'll snap, you see?
ビターチョコデコレーション
Misstep while they're watching, face a group lynching.
立つ鳥跡濁って糞のアート
But it's do or die! Survive insanity!
初めはあんな大層な大言壮語を並べたが
Bitter choco decoration.
嫌々も好きの内
You know that every now and then a "love" will bring you "pain".
「いやはやしかして今日は初めてで
Bitter choco decoration.
こんなとはね 君センスあるよ」
They're gonna leave you far behind, their art forever stained.
恋する季節にビターチョコデコレーション
Way back at the start, with dreams, I could impress.
恋する気持ちでビターチョコデコレーション
Now it's tossed aside, no one cares, no one obsessed.
F.U.C.K.Y.O.U
Sometimes we say no, but we're always meaning yes.
ビターチョコデコレーション
"Hey, I gotta say that today we were amazed."
皆が望む理想に憧れて
"Got a knack for things like that, that could blow us all away."
僕は大人にやっとなったよママ
Love in season, give a reason, bitter choco decoration.
明日のひと言のその先も遅刻は続くどこまでも
Love in feeling, give a meaning, bitter choco decoration.
あの日からのご加護だけは言葉の殻の
F.U.C.K.Y.O.U, bitter choco decoration.
ビターチョコデコレーション
I wanna be all that you need, I want to make it last.
恋する季節にビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration.
恋する気持ちでビターチョコデコレーション
I'm gonna burn it all away, my feelings into ash.
F.U.C.K.Y.O.U
Bitter choco decoration.
ビターチョコデコレーション
I'll kill my ego and my heart, and put them in the ground.
皆が望む理想に憧れて
Bitter choco decoration.
僕は大人にやっとなったよママ
I guess I grew up in the end, hey mom, look at me now.
明日のひと言のその先も遅刻は続くどこまでも
Surely here on out, from now until the end,
あの日のご加護だけは
hell will always follow me, even when I'm dead.
気持ちのままで石は飛ばずにやってこうぜ
Let's keep going as we feel without holding back.
思い出したんだあのときの気まずいそうなくらい
I remembered how awkward it felt back then.
やっぱいいや
Actually, never mind.
笑ってるけどどっかないてんだ
I'm smiling, but somewhere I'm crying.
人生味気ご褒美の日は
On days when life feels bland and unrewarded,
思ってるけどずっと貯めてんだ
I keep holding these feelings inside.
いつもの味呪いの愛が
The usual taste, this cursed love
擦り減って濁って愛ラブ自分
wears down and clouds over. I love myself.
さてそうやって籠って不干渉
So I shut myself away, unconcerned,
大きな時を過ごしてみるけど
trying to spend my time calmly, but...
壊れた傘みたいに立ってなるんだ
I end up standing there like a broken umbrella.
わがままに選んではポイ消して 理屈抜きで夢とか信じたい
Selfishly choosing, tossing away, erasing—I want to believe in dreams without reason.
ネットでどうかしちゃいまりおネットなんかじゃない
Going crazy online... No, it's not just the internet.
期待じゃん ここいいねをもっと つまんない朝景色のシンデレラ
It's all about expectations. Give me more likes, Cinderella of a boring morning view.
叶えたい 消えたい 歪んでいくんだ ボクとボクとの境界線
I want to make it come true, I want to vanish—the boundary line between me and myself is warping.
どれも世界だ どれも世界だ
Each one is a world, each one is a world.
叶えたい消えたい歪んでいくんだ ボクとボクとの境界線
I want to make it come true, I want to vanish—the boundary line between me and myself is warping.
君だけにわおしえてもいいか
Is it okay if I only tell you?
Pray in order myself, to myself or am I myself
I'm go where I don't recall, oh maybe I chose not to know
嫉妬じゃん ここいいねをもっと つまんない朝景色のシンデレラ
It's jealousy. Give me more likes here, Cinderella of a boring morning view.
わがままに選んでは後悔して 変わったつもりがいやになるんだ
Selfishly choosing, then regretting—I hate how I thought I changed.
うるさうるさい頭も期待外れだ 糸を切ってそろそろ息継ぎだ
My noisy, noisy head falls short of expectations. Cut the strings, it's time to catch my breath.
ネットでどうかしちゃいまりおネットなんかじゃない
Going crazy online... No, it's not just the internet.
暗いなんだって買っていたんだ 描いてみたって本音は死んでいた
Why was it so gloomy? Even when I tried drawing it out, my true feelings were dead.
選びたい 捨てたい 歪んでいくんだ ボクとボクとの境界線
I want to choose, I want to throw away—the boundary line between me and myself is warping.
どれも世界だ どれも世界だ
Each one is a world, each one is a world.
選びたい捨てたい歪んでいくんだ ボクとボクとの境界線
I want to choose, I want to throw away—the boundary line between me and myself is warping.
期待じゃん ここいいねをもっと つまんない朝景色のシンデレラ
It's expectations. Give me more likes, Cinderella of a boring morning view.
叶えたい 消えたい 歪んでいくんだ ボクとボクとの境界線
I want to make it come true, I want to vanish—the boundary line between me and myself is warping.
どれも世界だ どれも世界だ
Each one is a world, each one is a world.
叶えたい消えたい歪んでいくんだ ボクとボクとの境界線
I want to make it come true, I want to vanish—the boundary line between me and myself is warping.
君だけにわおしえてもいいか そしてそれすらもうどうでもいいか
Is it okay if I only tell you? And even that doesn't matter anymore.
はい！ということで、バック、バック、バックナンバー、秘密警察、ろう...ソーセージ、インターシャチの坂田クロエです！
Yes! And with that, performing 'Back Number', 'Secret Police', 'Rosé'... Sakamata Chloe here!
はい、今日は坂俣の卒業ライブに来てくださり、本当にありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you so much for coming to Sakamata's graduation live today!
え、ハッシュタグ、こちらの坂俣クロエ卒業ライブでぜひ感想を呟いてもらえると嬉しいです！
Um, I'd be so happy if you could tweet your thoughts using the hashtag for this Sakamata Chloe Graduation Live!
そしてもうすでにトレンド1位ということで、ありがとうございます！みんなありがとう！
And apparently it's already #1 on trending, thank you so much! Thank you everyone!
えー、アワーブライトパレードの、あのバンド、ビターチョコデコレーションギターごっこを歌わせていただきました。
Um, I got to sing 'Our Bright Parade', that band version, 'Bitter Choco Decoration', and play guitar pretend.
あのバンドではししし先輩とぺこら先輩にゲストに来ていただいて、ビターチョコデコレーションではかなけんのお二人に来ていただきました！ありがとうございます！
In 'That Band', Shishi-senpai and Pekora-senpai came as guests, and for 'Bitter Choco Decoration', Kanata and the others came! Thank you so much!
ちょっとどちらも違ったテイストではあると思うんですが、すごくかっこいい曲だったんじゃない？リシオク...どうどうでした？
I think both had different tastes, but weren't they super cool songs? How, how was it?
よかったらね、そちらのたくさんの愛も呟いてください、よろしくお願いします！
If you'd like, please tweet all that love too, thank you very much!
そして、えー坂俣のソロ曲ですね、アワーブライトパレードとギターごっこどちらも生で歌わさせていただいております。
And for Sakamata's solo songs, 'Our Bright Parade' and 'Guitar Gokko', I got to sing both live.
緊張しすぎて声が出ません！もう助けてください！
I was so nervous my voice wouldn't come out! Please help me!
本当に見守ってちょっと応援によろしくお願いします！おにが！おにが！おにが！マジで超緊張してるんで、よろしくおねがいします！
Please watch over me and cheer me on! Please, please, please, I'm super nervous, so please!
お、え、野号からなんかビデオレターが...きてるって！じゃあ見まーす、よろしくお願いします！
Oh, a video letter from Yagoo has arrived! Well then, I'll watch it, thank you!
クロエさん、また配信をご覧の皆さん、こんばんは。
Chloe-san, and everyone watching the stream, good evening.
カバー株式会社代表取締役の谷郷元昭です。
I'm Motoaki Tanigo, CEO of Cover Corp.
こんばんは！白いっすね。
Good evening! You're wearing white, huh?
そうですね、クロエさん、あの…
That's right. Chloe-san, um...
最初の印象としては初配信で、あの、見てですね、
My first impression from watching her debut stream was...
まあ、いい意味で図々しくて、まあ、このタレントさんすごく人気出るだろうなっていうふうに、あの、感じていました。
Well, in a good way, she was shameless, and I felt like, "Ah, this talent is going to be super popular."
またそうですね、印象に残っている活動内容としては、まあ、生放送で、あの、周年配信での、あの、
Also, as for memorable activities, during the anniversary live broadcast...
まあ、歌のパフォーマンスだったと思うんですが、非常に緊張感が、あの、こちらにも伝わってくるような感じで、
I think it was her singing performance. The tension was so palpable even on this end,
まあ、ドキドキしながら見守っていたのを覚えていて、今もですね、社長とか、あるいは、さくらみこさんのような、あの、先輩と絡まれている中で、こう自信を深めながら歌のパフォーマンスが上がっていくのを感じていて、非常に感動したのを、あの、今でも覚えています。
that I remember watching over her with a pounding heart. Even now, seeing her interact with seniors like Sora-san or Sakura Miko-san, I could feel her gaining confidence and improving her singing, and I still remember being deeply moved by it.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
はい、あの、最後になりますが、あの、3年間、あの、活動本当にお疲れ様でした。
Yes, and finally, thank you so much for your three years of activities.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
私からは非常に…なります。
From me, it's very...
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you!
いやあ、ありがたいですね、成長を、やごにみまもってもらっていたということで、
Man, I'm so grateful that Yagoo has been watching over my growth,
とってもとってもえーしに、ありがとうございます。
so thank you so much, AC...
はい、ということで、じゃあそろそろ次の曲に移りたいと思うんですが、ちょっとお水飲んでもいいですか？ごめんなさい。
Yes, and with that, I'd like to move on to the next song soon, but do you mind if I drink some water? Sorry!
お水飲みます。ありがとうございます。
I'll drink some water. Thank you very much.
はい、ということで、お水も飲んだところで、それでは次の曲に行きたいと思います が、
Alright, so now that I've had some water, let's move on to the next song.
次の曲は、初期の頃に歌みたを投稿したあの曲です！分かる人いる？
The next song is that one song I posted a cover of back in my early days! Does anyone know it?
ちょっと当ててみて今。
Try guessing it right now.
分かる？なかなか、あの、どうなんだろう、印象に残ってくれてるかなあ。
Do you know? I wonder if it left an impression on you guys.
どうでしょう。まだね、お水飲んでるとこだね。
What do you think? I'm still drinking water right now.
まだ水飲んでほしいっそ、みんな。うん。ありがと。いっぱいお水飲んで元気入れたよ。
You all want me to drink more water, huh? Yeah. Thank you. I drank lots of water and got my energy back.
大丈夫だよ。ありがとに。
It's okay. Thank you.
おって言ってる、あ、来るよ、そろそろ。おっ、おっ、えっ、あっ、えっ？
You're saying 'Oh'? Ah, it's coming soon. Oh? Oh? Eh? Ah? Eh?
フクロウ？ちがっ、アニマル？ちがっ、キャットラミング？ちがっ。
Owl? No. Animal? No. Catraming? No.
そう、当たりました！
That's right, you guessed it!
そこの君、正解です！
You right there, that's correct!
次の曲は、偽物人間40号です！
The next song is 'Imposter Human No. 40'!
それでは、聞いてください、偽物人間40号！
Now then, please listen to 'Imposter Human No. 40'!
めでめでたにになるわほんとさ
It really becomes a celebration, truly.
まだジャンキーじゃんきのままで
Still remaining all jagged and raw.
偽物人間40号
Imposter Human No. 40
ほんとにこのままでいいんだと思ってる
Frightened that staying like this is really okay,
散々転げ回ってあがいてる
I've been tumbling and struggling everywhere.
ほらやっぱりやっぱりつまんない晩に執着に寄り添って機械じみた意味を追っている
Look, as expected, it's boring, clinging to a dull evening, chasing mechanical meanings.
知ってる知ってる使えた争う言葉使ってみたってあの人のようにはなれないのです
I know, I know. Even if I try using those worn-out, combative words, I can't become like that person.
誰事も推しごくまっとうさされどういった日々だ
Every little thing is so terribly righteous... What kind of days are these?
しょせんぼくは偽物なのさ壊れる前に壊してしまう前に
After all, I'm a fake. Before I break, before I shatter it all,
めでめでたにになるわほんとさ
It really becomes a celebration, truly.
まだジャンキーじゃんきだ
Still all jagged.
もう飽き飽きなんだ
I'm already so sick and tired of it.
めでたいゴミ溜まりへ向かうようなバキバキ人間なんだ
Heading towards a celebratory trash heap, I'm a totally shattered human.
愚かな心臓人間なんだ
I'm a foolish, heartless human.
ああ曖昧な自分のこと嫌いだし
Ah, I hate my own ambiguous self,
あああんたには分からないんだって思ってる
and I think you wouldn't understand it.
ほらやっぱりやっぱりつまんない散々描いたがよく発だったあの日描いた未来はこんなに
Look, as expected, it's boring. I'd imagined it so many times, but that future I drew that day is so...
耐え難く流れ込んできた忘れたい過去が
painfully flooding in, a past I want to forget.
漏れ出す老いる自傷に落ちる
Leaking out, falling into aging self-harm.
ふらふら脱いで
Staggering, shedding it off,
終わらせてしまおうか
shall we just end it all?
めでめで疲れたよ
I'm so exhausted, really,
本当さ
truly.
目で見て病みになるわ 本当さ
Seeing it makes me sick, really,
まだジャンキージャンキーなままで
still being a junkie, junkie.
めでめで誰か助けてくれ...
Congratulations, someone save me...
めでめで足一つ出せずに
Congratulations, without being able to take a step,
もう飽き飽きなんだ
I'm already so sick of it.
めでめで自分さえ守れないような
Unable to even protect oneself,
ファンキーファンキー人間なんて
what a funky, funky person...
ああジャンキージャンキージャンキー...ジャンキー人間なんて
Ah, what a junkie, junkie... junkie person...
ああ クソが
Ah, dammit!
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we exchanged,
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes and confirm it.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the surging darkness and move forward.
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I be able to see the lost future
私ここでまた見ることができるの?
here once again?
溢れ出した不安の影を何度も裂いて
Shattering the overflowing shadows of anxiety again and again,
この世界歩んでこう
let's walk through this world.
とめどなく刻まれた 時は今始まり告げ
Time, ticked away endlessly, now announces the beginning,
変わりない思いをのせ
carrying our unchanging feelings,
閉ざされた扉開けよう
let's open the closed door.
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来を描くため
My awakened heart began to run to paint the future,
難しい道で立ち止まっても
even if I stop on a difficult path,
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っていてくれるから
the sky is always waiting with a beautiful blue,
怖くない もう何があっても挫けない
so I'm not afraid, I won't give up no matter what.
振り返れば仲間がいて
Looking back, my friends were there,
気づけば優しく包まれてた
before I knew it, I was warmly embraced.
何もかもが歪んだ世界で
In a world where everything was distorted,
唯一信じられるここが救いだった
this place I could solely believe in was my salvation.
喜びも悲しみも 分け合えば強まる想い
If we share joy and sorrow, our feelings grow stronger,
この声が届くのなら
if this voice can reach you,
きっと奇跡はおこせるだろう
I'm sure we can make a miracle happen.
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we exchanged,
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes and confirm it.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the surging darkness and move forward.
どんなに大きな壁があっても 超えてみせるからきっと
No matter how big a wall there is, I'll surely overcome it,
明日信じて祈って
believing in tomorrow and praying.
壊れた世界で彷徨って私は
Wandering in a broken world, I
引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
arrived as if drawn toward you.
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来を描くため
My awakened heart began to run to paint the future,
難しい道で立ち止まっても 空はきれいな青さでいつも待っていてくれるから
even if I stop on a difficult path, the sky is always waiting with a beautiful blue,
怖くない もう何があっても挫けない ずっと明日待ってて
so I'm not afraid, I won't give up no matter what, always waiting for tomorrow.
何もかもが歪んだ世界で 唯一信じられるここが救いだった
In a world where everything was distorted, this place I could solely believe in was my salvation.
喜びも悲しみも 分け合えば強まる想い
If we share joy and sorrow, our feelings grow stronger,
この声が届くのなら きっと奇跡はおこせるだろう
if this voice can reach you, I'm sure we can make a miracle happen.
交わした約束忘れないよ 目を閉じ確かめる
I won't forget the promise we exchanged, I close my eyes and confirm it.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the surging darkness and move forward.
どんなに大きな壁があっても 超えてみせるからきっと
No matter how big a wall there is, I'll surely overcome it,
明日信じて祈って 壊れた世界で彷徨って
believing in tomorrow and praying, wandering in a broken world,
私は引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
I arrived as if drawn toward you.
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来を描くため
My awakened heart began to run to paint the future,
難しい道で立ち止まっても
even if I stop on a difficult path,
壊れた世界でその夜って私は
In a broken world that night, I
引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
arrived as if drawn toward you.
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来を描くため
My awakened heart began to run to paint the future,
難しい道で立ち止まっても
even if I stop on a difficult path,
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っていてくれるから
the sky is always waiting with a beautiful blue.
交わした約束 忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made.
目を閉じ 確かめる
I close my eyes and confirm it.
押し寄せた闇 振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the closing darkness and press forward.
もう何があったって もうくじけない
No matter what happens, I won't give up.
ずっと明日待って
Waiting for tomorrow, forever...
くらいおんぼばっか見てないで
Don't just stare at gloomy things,
うらぱっぱっぱらりら踊れよ
Dance away, ura-papappa-rarira!
魔界学校の優等生 華やかな我が儘称えよ
Praise the honor student of demon school and her dazzling selfishness!
いないいないばぁでこっち向いて
Peek-a-boo, look over here,
したたかな未来を逆せよ 次第愛まって高まって
Turn the cunning future around, let love grow and surge,
またパワー放て黒魔術
And unleash black magic power once more!
聖なる獄に集えよ 闇に震え震えるベロス 切実に響く言葉は 打っ千切れ破kyo パラダイス
Gather in the sacred prison, trembling in the dark—belos!
綺麗に心奥底まで届け
Reach cleanly all the way to the depths of the heart,
これからも私のもとで 不思議な力打ち放て 世界を笑顔になっちゃって
From now on, by my side, unleash mysterious power and make the whole world smile!
うらぱっぱっぱらりら歌えば 一生一緒だよネ
If we sing ura-papappa-rarira, we'll be together forever, right?
くらいもっと無視してないで 生まれたからさぁまぁ踊れよ
Don't just ignore me, since you were born, come on, dance!
世界外見そらさないで 今はとどおのれてとなえて
Don't look away from the world, chant now as it echoes!
よんよん待ってあっち向いて 今はまだ心の準備を
Wait a second, look away, my heart isn't quite ready yet,
期待裂ぎって固まって うらぱっぱっぱ動け空魔術
Expectations tearing and solidifying, move with sorcery!
我らに続け今宵の 闇を破れメシアよ 打つべきものその名は 眠りの発祥パラダイス
Follow us tonight, break the darkness, oh Messiah!
綺麗に心奥底まで届け 白黒つけてあげるから
Reach cleanly to the depths of the heart, I'll clear things up for you,
不思議な力振りかざして みんなで笑顔になっちゃって
Brandish mysterious power and make everyone smile!
うらぱっぱっぱらりら歌えば 一生一緒だよね 絶対一緒だよね
If we sing ura-papappa-rarira, we'll be together forever, absolutely together!
ひらりひらりと紫色に染まって
Fluttering and dyeing in a purple hue,
これからもあなたの元で 奇跡の呪文解き放て 咲かせる笑顔の花を
From now on, by your side, unleash miraculous spells and let the flowers of smiles bloom!
綺麗に心奥底まで届け これからも変わらないままで
Reach cleanly to the depths of the heart, staying unchanged from now on,
不思議な力ほら宿して 世界を笑顔になっちゃって
Behold, harbor mysterious power and make the world smile!
うらぱっぱっぱらりら歌えば 日常一緒だよね 絶対一緒だよね
If we sing ura-papappa-rarira, we'll be together every day, absolutely together!
はい、ということでメジ・オブ・ヴァイオレットでした！ありがとう！
Right, so that was 'Mage of Violet'! Thank you!
しょうじゅむぎーずのみんなありがとう！
Thank you to all the fans!
えー、ふりーす！ありがとう呼んでくれて！
Um, Freese! Thanks for having me!
いや本当にね、しおじゅうせんぱいがちゃんと坂本のこの卒業ライブに来てくれて、こんなに愛を示してくれるなんて！
Seriously, Shioju-senpai actually came to the graduation live and showed so much love!
本当に最高です！それだけでですか？
It's truly the best! Is that really all?
え、違ったんですか？
Wait, was it something else?
いやいやいやいやいや、やれよ、うん、あい、そう、そうそうそう...
No, no, no! Just do it, yeah, love, right...
はい、あい、あいあいあい、あいだよ！
Yeah, love, love, love, it's love!
汐音、ねえ。
Shion, hey.
シオン先輩とはさ、ホロライブに入ってからめちゃめちゃ仲良くなりましたよね。
Ever since joining Hololive, Shion-senpai and I have gotten super close, haven't we?
なった！ねえ！
We did! Hey!
そうだよ、ねえ！
That's right, hey!
いろんな場所も行ったしね。
We went to all kinds of places too.
いや本当にいろんな場所行った。
Yeah, truly, we went to all kinds of places.
ね、ロケも行ったしね！
Right, we went on location shoots too!
水族館もね！
And the aquarium too!
愛の告白も受けてくれたし。
And you even accepted my confession of love.
あれ？記憶がない。
Huh? I don't remember that.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
いや、そんなこともあった！
No, stuff like that happened!
超気になっちゃって。そんなこともあった！
I got super curious. Stuff like that happened!
うん、そうそうそう。そうだよね、覚えてるよ。
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's right, I remember.
そうだよね、覚えてるよね。
That's right, you remember, right?
うん。
Yeah.
いや、そんなこと、いろんなことしたよね、配信とかね。
Yeah, we did all sorts of things, like streams.
いろんなことして、いろんなことしゃべったね。
We did various things and talked about various things.
森も行ったしね。
We even went to the woods.
森行ったね。クリスマスに森。
We went to the woods. The woods on Christmas.
そうだね。
That's right.
いや、楽しかったりしちゃったね。
Man, it was actually really fun.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
卒業した後も仲良くしてください。
Please stay good friends even after graduation.
どうしよっかな。ええ！うそ！もう返しちゃおうかな、今日。ダメだよ、ね？
What should I do? Eh! No way! Should I return it already today? No way, right?
早いよ！
That's too fast!
もう、どうでもよくなっちゃった、なんかすべてが。うそだよ、うそだよ。
Man, I don't even care anymore about anything. Just kidding, just kidding.
なんか、当たり前でしょ？当たり前。そんなこと聞かなくても。
I mean, isn't that obvious? Obvious. Even without asking.
いや、聞いたほうがいいよ。聞かなくてもわかるでしょ。
No, it's better to ask. You should know even without asking.
もう、みんな大変なことになるとこだったね。「帰る」っていうね。
We were almost in a huge mess. Saying "I'm going home."
本人が帰るっていう。もに不在のね。いや、卒業ライブになっちゃうからね。
The person herself saying she's going home. Mori being absent. Well, it would become a graduation live.
そう、いろんな思い出を積み上げてきたんですけど、坂田的にはまだまだちょっと思い出作りたいななんて思ったりなんかもして。
Yeah, we've piled up various memories, but from Sakamata's perspective, I feel like I still want to make more memories.
ちょっと今日は、そう、せっかくホロライブで過ごすその時間最後だと思うので、ちょっとお願いしちゃおうかな。
So today, since I think this is the last time we'll spend such time in Hololive, I might make a request.
断れないよね？はい、聞いてくれますよね。
You can't refuse, right? Yes, you'll listen, right?
卒業しますから、断れないやつだ、これ。これ運以外ないんだ。ない。はいと運以外そんなしてないんだ。うん、うん。
Since I'm graduating, this is something I can't refuse. There's nothing other than luck for this. None. There's nothing other than "yes" and luck. Yeah, yeah.
よかった！オッケー！しょうがないよね。こんなこと言われるんだって！
Great! Okay! Can't be helped, right? To be told something like this!
あ、じゃあ、まずなんか、あんまり、ちゃんと答えてくれなかったりとかはぐらかされたりするので、坂田に大好きを伝えてほしいです。
Ah, then, first, since you sometimes don't answer properly or dodge the question, I want you to tell Sakamata how much you love her.
え、どうしたどうした？なんで、どこに笑う要素あんの？大好きを伝えてほしい。伝えてほしいです。
Eh, what's wrong? Why, where's the funny part? I want you to tell me you love me. I want you to tell me.
やった！言ってよ！言ってよ！わかった、わかった。それでね、まずはって何、待って？
Yay! Say it! Say it! Understood, understood. And then, first, what, wait?
あ、1つめってこと？よく気づきましたね。気づいちゃったか。1つめってこと？
Ah, you mean the first one? You noticed well. Did you notice? You mean the first one?
まずはから入ってたよね、今。言えないと思ったから言ったんだけど。まあまずは、まあまあ確かに最初だよね。
You started with "first," didn't you? I said it because I thought you couldn't. Well first, well, true, it's the beginning.
坂田、はい。大好きだよ！やった！やった！今日めっちゃがんばそう。やった！やった！
Sakamata, yes. I love you! Yay! Yay! Today's gonna be super tough. Yay! Yay!
こんな意気込んで、こんな意気込むんだ。うれしい。じゃあ、ちょっとよしよしってしてほしいな。
Getting this pumped up, really getting pumped up. I'm happy. So, I want you to pat my head.
え、これ次はってこと？あ、そうですしょ？はい、タスクに。
Eh, you mean next? Ah, is that so? Yes, to the tasks.
ああ、2。あ、これ、これ完了しないといけないやつ？あ、そうですよ。どうぞ。よかった、よしよし。やった！うれしい！えらいね！よっしゃ、最後だな。
Ah, 2. Ah, is this one we have to complete? Ah, that's right. Go ahead. Great, headpats. Yay! I'm happy! Good job! Alright, it's the last one.
じゃあ、大いなる、大いなる。じゃあ、2個まで撮ってるんで、もう多分3つ目もいけるから。
Well then, a great, great. Well, we've taken up to 2, so maybe we can do a 3rd one.
え、じゃあ、シオン先輩の犬になりたいから、あの、坂田のことワンちゃんみたいな感じで、よしよしってしてほしいなって。
Eh, then, since I want to be Shion-senpai's dog, I want you to treat me like a puppy and pat my head.
これ卒業配信だよね？あ、そうです。え？それで行っていいの？
This is a graduation stream, right? Ah, that's right. Eh? Is it okay to go with that?
それ、プライドとか、ないの、なんか？なんか、ないの？アイドルとしてのなんか、ねえ、ねえの？わあ、わあ、わあ、わあ、え、よしよし、かわいいワンちゃんだね。
Do you have no pride or anything? Is there nothing? As an idol, like, hey, don't you have any? Wow, wow, wow, wow, eh, pat pat, what a cute puppy.
あ、じゃあその通信ちょっと蹴ってもらっていいですか？ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って。待って、ちょっと待って！本当にこれ大丈夫？はい。これ大丈夫？大丈夫ですよ。
Ah, then could you kick that connection? Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute. Wait, wait a minute! Is this really okay? Yes. Is this okay? It's okay.
やっぱ、最後に夢かなえたいっすよね。かねさせてください。もうちょっと聞いてない。
As expected, I want to make my dream come true at the end. Please let me have it. Wait, I'm not listening.
はい。じゃあ。えい！もっと強く！もっと！もっと！もっと人蹴ったことないんですけど。もっと！えい！あ、最高です！
Yes. Well then. Ei! Hit harder! More! More! I've never kicked a person before. More! Ei! Ah, this is the best!
やったー！待って！最高っていうのは、え？ちょっと、どうした？
Yay! Wait! When you say the best, eh? Wait, what's wrong?
いやいやいやいや、シオン先輩だからもっと仲良くしてくださいね。
No no no no, since you're Shion-senpai, please get even closer with me.
いつ？
When?
ちょっと、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょっと待って
Wait, wait, wait, wait a second!
え、どうしたんですか？
Huh, what is it?
いやちょっと、いや、ちょっと
No, um, no, just...
いや嬉しいな、こうやって一緒に過ごせてね。
I'm so happy we get to spend this time together.
ちょっと、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょっと
Wait, wait, wait, wait...
え、嬉しいね。嬉しい。嬉しい。
Ah, I'm so happy. So happy.
これからもずっと一緒にいようね。
Let's stay together forever, okay?
え、ずっと、ずっと一緒？
Wait, together forever?
うん、うん、ずっと一緒にいようね。
Yeah, yeah, let's stay together forever.
そうだね、いようね。
That's right, let's do that.
か、影？これ？影、影かな？
A-A shadow? Is this? A shadow?
なんか、後ろからずっと付いてきて……影かと思った！
It's been following right behind us... I thought it was a shadow!
え、これ、これだったの？
Wait, was this it all along?
いや、そうですよ。
Yes, of course.
あ、今叶ったんだ、じゃあ。叶いました！
Oh, so it came true just now! It came true!
ありがとうございます、本当に！よかったー！
Thank you so much, really! I'm so glad!
え、もしかして、これ、だってもう帰っててたもんね？先輩ずっと帰っててたもんね？
Wait, but you were already heading back, weren't you? You kept trying to go back!
そうですよ。
That's right.
危なかったー、よかった。
That was close, I'm glad.
先輩のおかげでね、この先も卒業ライブができるということで。
Thanks to you, senpai, we can keep going with the graduation live.
続くってことですね？
So it continues?
そうです。
That's right.
いや、よかった。じゃあ、まあ加速。
Man, I'm relieved. Well then, time to accelerate.
世界救うためだもんね、じゃあ。
To save the world, right?
あ、そうですよ。
Oh, absolutely.
そうだよね。
True, true.
この後も頑張りますから！
We'll keep giving it our all!
頑張ってね、それは。それはがんば……頑張ってね。
Do your best, then. You better... do your best.
いや、衝撃で、衝撃的すぎて、ちょっと忘れられないな、忘れられない。忘れられない経験になった。
Man, that was too shocking, I'll never forget it. It's an unforgettable experience.
忘れられない思い出になった！
It became an unforgettable memory!
やったー！衝撃！
Yay! Total shock!
よかった！
I'm so glad!
本当に。衝撃だった。
Seriously. Such a shock.
本当に。でも、ありがとうございました！
Truly. But thank you so much!
ね、こちらこそ、ありがとう。
No, thank you.
ね、また今度遊ぼうね。言ってたやつね。言ってたやつ、うん。行こう、行こうね。
Let's hang out again sometime. Like we talked about. Yeah, let's definitely go.
はい！じゃあ、頑張ってね、また。はい、ありがとう！ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Yes! Well then, good luck! Thank you! Bye-bye!
ああ、最高だったな。軽蔑もされたかったんだよね。最高。
Ah, that was the best. I wanted to be looked down on a little too. The best.
じゃあ、ていうことで、次の曲頑張りたいと思います。よろしくお願いします！
Well then, with that said, we'll do our best on the next song. Thank you for watching!
そこに膝を付け
Drop to your knees right there,
敗て捨てるような現実は
and shatter this defeated reality.
一刀両断 叩き切れ
Cut it down in one swift stroke,
終わりなき輪廻に迷いし者よ
you who wander through endless reincarnation.
我らエデンの星を滑るもの 秘密結社
We are the rulers of Eden's star, Secret Society
ホロックス！ 天まで上がれ！
holoX! Rise up to the heavens!
どうしようもないこの世界
In this hopeless world,
どうして走るんだか
what are we even running for?
週末告げる鐘が鳴る
The bell signaling the weekend rings out.
ラパパ　手を取り合って　スリップしようぜ
Lapapa, holding hands, let's slip away,
陰キャも陽キャもシンガソング
introverts and extroverts alike, singing a song.
気持ちいいことだけがすべて落ちていく　闇の底へ
Falling straight down to the depths of darkness, where only pleasure remains.
甘い甘いメロディほらどうぞどうぞ　手を取り合うウェル
Sweet, sweet melody, here, go ahead, welcoming each other hand in hand.
もう逃げられない
There's no running away anymore.
ほら　闇に染まれば　世界を塗り替えろ
Look, if you're dyed in darkness, repaint the world.
望めば連れてやろう　すべて
If you wish it, I'll take you through everything.
常識　破り捨てろ
Tear away and cast aside common sense.
クズクズクズと痛い王セン　火をつけろ
Ignite the painful impulses of worthless scum.
すべてを暗い尽くせ　秘密を教えてやろう
Swallow everything up in darkness, and I'll share a secret with you.
悪のカリスマは導くぞトミクサー　正義とか知らないし地ならしいていざない
The charismatic villain leads the mixer, knowing no justice, leveling the path to guide you.
真面目に不真面目　電車のつうかぎりて　望み求め願い叶え　世界征服
Earnestly mischievous, past the train's boundary, seeking desires and granting wishes for world conquest.
ラパパ手を取り合ってスウィングしようぜ退屈な世界へバイバイバイ
Lapapa, holding hands, let's swing to a tedious world, bye-bye-bye.
覚めることのない夢を見せる　ほらお眠りなさい
I'll show you an unending dream, so go on and fall asleep.
もっともっと遠くへほらどうぞどうぞ行きたいでしょ
Even further away, come on, you want to go, don't you?
もうやめられない
You can't stop now.
ほら悪に染まれば　世界を塗り替えろ
Look, once you're tainted by evil, repaint the world.
ゴミもものあたえよう　すべて
Let's give all things, even the dust, completely over.
ブルーブルーを書き換えろ　くるくる回し尽くせ　行き尽くせ
Rewrite the blue, spin it around to the very end, go all the way.
すべての曲がりものへ　秘密を教えてやろう
To all things twisted, I'll teach you a secret.
火は熟した　狂気の宴の始まりだ　貴様ら準備はいいか　カトモクセヨ
The fire is ripe, the banquet of madness begins! Are you ready, you scoundrels?
クロエ！クロエ！手上げろ！手上げろ！
Chloe! Chloe! Raise your hands! Raise your hands!
いろは！いろは！叫べでござる！
Iroha! Iroha! Shout it out, de gozaru!
今夜！今夜！踊れ！踊れ！
Tonight! Tonight! Dance! Dance!
そこに跪け！
Kneel before us!
世界を手にするholoX！
holoX taking the world!
世界を変えてくholoX！
holoX changing the world!
ルイ姉！ルイ姉！！
Lui-nee! Lui-nee!!
もっと！もっと！
More! More!
ラプラス！ラプラス！！
Laplus! Laplus!!
最後は全員行くぞ！
Everyone, let's go for the finale!
holoX！holoX！
holoX! holoX!
世界を手にするholoX！
holoX taking the world!
世界を変えてくholoX！
holoX changing the world!
世界をこの手にholoX！！
holoX holding the world in our hands!!
心を解き放て
Release your heart...
ほらどうぞどうぞ 身を任せて
Come on, just surrender yourself...
もう逃げられない ほら闇に染まれば
You can't escape once you're dyed in darkness,
世界を塗り替えろ 望めばくれてやろう
Repaint the world, I'll give you whatever you wish!
常識破り捨てろ ぐるぐる狂い倒せ火を付けろ
Tear up common sense, spin wildly, set it on fire!
常識 破り捨てろ
Tear up common sense,
くるくる狂い倒せ 火を付けろ
spin wildly, go crazy, set it on fire!
すべてを喰らいつくせ
Swallow everything up!
秘密を教えてやろう
I'll share a secret with you!
というわけで
So, that means...
常夜リペイントでしたー！
That was "Jouya Repaint"!
盛り上がったかー！
Did you get hyped?!
やっぱこの曲だな！
This really is the song!
holoXですね！
It's holoX!
そうだね！
That's right!
あとはルイ姉にか...
And Lui-nee...
一番好きな曲！え、分かる？
My absolute favorite song! Eh, you know?
常夜リペイント一番いい！
"Jouya Repaint" is the best!
常夜リペイントかな
I guess "Jouya Repaint".
あの一番好きなんだ
I love that one the most.
あ、フォースフェスの思い出も
Ah, the memories of 4th Fes too.
個人差がヤバイ
Individual differences are crazy.
みんなでね立ったもんね
We all stood together, right?
マジでバグりかけていた瞬間みんな
Everyone was literally glitching out for a second.
感情揺れすぎて
Emotions were fluctuating too much.
分かったもんね
We understood, right?
あれはいい思い出です
That's a good memory.
え、覚えてる？
Eh, do you remember?
覚えてますよ！
I remember!
最初は忘れてたけど、覚えてる！
At first I forgot, but I remember!
いやでもすごくない？
I mean, isn't that amazing?
私たち、あの、伝えたいことが
We, um, have something to tell you...
あ、あって
Ah, there is.
ク・ロ・エ・い・ま・ま・で・あ・り・が・と・う！
Thank you for everything, Chloe!
いや、これ誕生日のやつや
Man, this is like a birthday thing.
誕生日のふざけのやつじゃん！どういうこと？
This is just a birthday prank! What's this?
なんかエモい感じかと思った
I thought it was gonna be an emotional vibe.
エモくないの？え？
Not emotional? Eh?
やばば、これ
Yababa, this...
エロくないよ！
It's not lewd!
エロい、エロいって！エロくないよ！
Lewd? I said lewd! It's not lewd!
やめてください！ラ行にすな！
Stop it! Don't put it in the "ra" column!
いや、じゃあクロエだからリアルなやつね
Well, since it's Chloe, let's make it real.
やるんだね、まあこれは
You're gonna do it, well, this is...
まあこれこそがホロックスらしさですもんね
Well, this is classic holoX, right?
いやでも思い出し補正でエモくなるでしょ
Well, nostalgia correction makes it emotional.
いや、エモくなるか、なんでも
Well, it gets emotional, whatever.
今日はエモくなっちゃった
It got emotional today.
いや、むしろこれぐらいの方が嬉しい
Honestly, this amount is happier.
まだある、てかありがとうございます、本当に
There's more, I mean thank you, really.
みんなでシクシク
Everyone sniffling...
うう、うう、はね
Sobbing, sob...
まあね
Well, yeah.
いや、これからも笑顔で出ていきたいからね
Well, we want to keep going out with smiles.
ああ、いいこと言った
Ah, well said.
まああの、ホロライブはあれだけど、ホロックスは関係ないから
Well, hololive is one thing, but holoX has nothing to do with it.
そう、いつでも味方になってあげるから
Yeah, we can always be on your side.
別に、あの、最後の、最後のホロックスの歌の最後でさ、歌えるからさ
I mean, at the very end of the holoX song, you can sing it.
ボロ泣きしてね
Crying your eyes out.
できる、できるか？あ、でも泣ける、カラオケね
Can you do it? Ah, but you'll cry at karaoke.
ホロックスのあの、ブルで見てやれ
Look at it on holoX's Blu-ray.
マジで、味とカラオケ味とカラオケ
Seriously, flavor and karaoke...
できる、できる
You can, you can.
あの時と振りも違ってくるしね
And the choreography will be different from back then.
そうだよね、そうなんだよね、新振りになってますからね、今や
That's right, it's got new choreography now.
いや本当にね、ありがとうございます、本当に
Thank you so much, really.
いいよ
It's fine.
ちょっと、こちらこそ
Here too.
嬉しいです、なんかこうやって
I'm so glad, doing this...
見送ってもらえるというか
...seeing me off.
一緒にね、楽しい時も辛い時も同期として頑張ってきたなって思うから、本当に本当に嬉しいです、ありがとうございます
Working hard together through good times and bad as generations, I'm truly happy, thank you.
クロエ！
Chloe!
泣かないで！
Don't cry!
見送りたくないんだよ！
I don't want to see you off!
いや、やめなさい！やめなさい！
Hey, stop it! Stop it!
待って、待って、ちょっと！技術的になんとか大丈夫？
Wait, wait, hold on! Are you technically okay?
映って大丈夫なの、これ
Is it okay to be shown on camera?
映って大丈夫なの？
Is it okay if it's shown?
黒歴史入ったか？
Did you enter dark history?
いや、でもね
Well, but...
今日はちゃんに入ってきた
Today it properly came in.
え、あ、私入ってないよ？じゃあくっつける？
Eh, ah, I didn't get in? Then attach it?
本当によかった！
It's wonderful!
本当だよ。
Yeah, exactly.
入ってないやついます？
Is there any other person who hasn't spoken?
ちょっと入ってないやつ、入ってないやつ、ちょっと待って。
Wait, haven't you entered yet?
入ってないやつよ。
Go on, get in.
なんでこんな
Why would we do this?
素敵な時にさ。
At such a wonderful time...
違う違う違う違う。やっぱ輝くのはさ、今日じゃない。
Wait, it shouldn't be Chloe's turn to shine.
今日、クロヱが、いっかなと思って。
Chloe should be the one—
横切ってくれてもいいよ。
You should cross over!
横切るアングルとか狙ってさ、汚れなくていい。
A cross-over angle to aim for without getting dirty.
きれいに来て、それは。
That would be clean, wouldn't it?
いや、本当にありがとうね。
Yeah, seriously, thank you.
もう、だから。
So...
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
また、これからも
Well, from now on, too...
ホロックス、4人が頑張っているところ見届けていきたいので、
We want to watch over HoloX—
またこれからも、ホロックスとしても、そしてホロライブのメンバーとしても頑張ってください！応援してます！
Please keep doing your best as HoloX and as HoloLive members! We're rooting for you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いや、これクロヱのさ、パート取り合いだね、これね。
Yeah, this is a tug-of-war for Chloe's part, right?
確かに！
That's true!
手を上げろ！手を上げろ！
Raise your hand, raise your hand!
いや、で見たい！
I want to see it!
いや、あれ全員で自分の名前言うの、クロヱので。
Yeah, everyone say their own name, like "Chloe's"!
ちょっとやってみる？
Let's try it!
うるさい！うるさい！
That's too loud!
そういうパートじゃない！
That's not that kind of part!
今日は誰々のパターンは？
Today's pattern is like...
もう一日ずつさ、クロヱのコールマネーするにしような！
Day by day, let's make it Chloe's call-out, shall we?
いやだもう！
No way!
やめたら好き勝手ってやられる！誰かからそれを見守っててください。
If you stop, you'll have your way with us! Someone watch over that!
はい！見守りますので。
Yeah, we'll watch over it!
好き勝手やってやる！
I'll have my way with you!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
こちらこそ、ありがとうございました！
Thank you too!
お疲れ様でした！
Good work today!
元気で行く！
Let's go with energy!
今回もあれですよね、頑張ってくださいということで、
This time, too, is like, "Please do your best," so—
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
待って、まだあるよ、クロヱ！
Wait, there's still more, Chloe!
クロヱ、まだあるよ！
Chloe, there's still more!
うちら、5人での最後の曲！
It's our last song with the five of us!
悲しい曲だね！
A sad one!
いや、でも本当に、みんなでさ、せっかく揃うのでさ、入ろうよ。
Yeah, but really, everyone's together, so let's join in!
揃って入ろうよ。
Let's join in!
いいよ、いいよ。
It's fine, it's fine!
じゃあ、行きましょう！
Well then, let's go!
はい、はい。
Yes, yes.
聞いてください。
Please listen.
せーの、サマータイムレコード！
Ready, set... Summertime Record!
サマタイムレコード
Summertime Record
昨日の今日も晴天で
Yesterday and today are clear, too,
入道雲を見ていた
and I was watching the cumulus clouds.
気怠いくらいの快晴だ
It's so clear I can hardly stand it.
徐々に目を閉じて
Slowly closing my eyes,
「それ」はどうも簡単に
"That" is so simple,
思い出せないような様で
it feels impossible to recall.
年を取った現状に
I was immersed in the reality
浸ってたんだよ
of getting older.
大人ぶった作戦で 不思議な合図立てて
Acting like adults with a strange sign—
「行こうか、今日も戦争だ」
"Let's go, it's war today too."
立ち向かって 手を取った
We stood up and took each other's hands.
理不尽なんて当然で
Unreasonableness is only natural,
独りぼっち 強いられて
standing alone, feeling empowered.
迷った僕は
I, lost,
憂鬱になりそうになってさ
was about to fall into melancholy.
背高草を分けて
Parting the tall grass,
滲む太陽睨んで
drinking in the sinking sun,
君はさ、こう言ったんだよ
you said to me this:
「孤独だったら、おいでよ」
"If you're lonely, call out to me."
騒がしさがノックして
The noise mocks us,
生まれた感情さえも
and even the nascent emotions
頭に浮かんでは萎んだ
fade away as they float in my head.
「幻なのかな？」
"Is it just an illusion?"
秘密基地に集まって
Gathering at our secret base,
「楽しいね」って単純な あの頃を思い出して
remembering those simple times
話をしよう
let's talk.
飛行機雲飛んで行って
Contrails flying across the sky,
「眩しいね」って泣いていた
"It's dazzling," we cried.
君はどんな顔だっけ
What kind of face did you make back then?
なぜだろう、思い出せないな
For some reason, I can't remember.
痛いくらいに現実は
Reality is painful enough
足早に駆け抜けた
to run away ahead of time.
選んだ今日は平凡で
The present we chose is ordinary
崩れそうになる日々さ
and feels like it's about to collapse.
痛いくらいの現実は
It's dazzling, but the reality is...
足早に駆け抜けた
to run away ahead of time.
選んだ今日は平凡で
The present we chose is ordinary
崩れそうになる日々さ
and feels like it's about to collapse.
昨日の今日も延長戦
Yesterday and today are extended battles.
大人ぶった作戦で不思議な合図立てて
with clouds rolling by.
「行こうか、今日も戦争だ」と
"Let's go, it's war today," we said,
立ち向かって 手を取った
as we faced each other and took hands.
晴れるくらいの快晴だ
A dazzling summer sky,
徐々に目を閉じて
closing my eyes slowly.
「それ」はどうも簡単に
"That" was so simple,
思い出しやしない様で
yet I can't seem to remember.
年を取った現状に浸ってたんだよ
Lost in the present, older now.
僕たちでいようよ
Let's stay together forever.
騒がしさがノックして
The noise knocked at my door,
生み出された感情さえも
and even newborn feelings.
秘密基地に集まって
Gathered in our secret base,
あの頃を思い出して話をしよう
we talked about those simple days.
涼しいねって言い合った
A clear summer sky,
「さようなら」しよう
let's say our goodbyes.
秘密基地に集まって
Gathered in our secret base,
笑い合った夏の日に
we laughed away the summertime blues.
また何処かで思い出して出会えるかなって
And we might meet so I will draw it again.
ゲストパート見ていただきありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching the guest part!
あのですね
*laughs*
収録時期が
Actually, the recording time...
あのホロックスライブより前なんですよ
was before the hololive concert!
あの見てて分かったと思うんですけど
Even though I realized it while watching,
言っていることがね、人格変わっちゃったんかっていうくらい全然違うんですけど
my personality seemed to have changed.
笑って分かかり「イエーイ！」みたいな感じになってるんですけど
Well, laughing makes it clear, "Yay!" sort of thing.
あの、だいぶ前に撮影してて
I had filmed it quite a while before.
なのでね、結局泣いちゃったって言う
So in the end, I cried.
みんな泣いちゃったってやつなんですけど
Everyone ended up crying.
でもなんか、ホロックスらしい一面が
Even so, it was hololive-esque,
こうやってね、また見れてよかったなと思えます
and I'm glad we could share this again.
ありがとうございます。そしてゲストについてなんですけど
Thank you! And speaking of the guests,
もう、結構序盤から分かってたっていうコメントで
I actually knew from quite early on...
実は今回ホロックスのメンバーでゲストに来ていただいていました
that holoX members were coming as guests.
スイちゃん先輩とね、あのクッキングだったりとか
With Suisei-senpai, we did cooking,
ポラケ先輩とハンバーガーだったりかなけんでお料理
with Kanata-senpai we did ASMR and survival,
で、今回はなずとき、リアル脱出（笑）そしてシオン先輩とはバンジージャンプと動物園
and with Shion-senpai, bungee jumping and zoos.
まあもしね、動画まだ見てない子いたら
If you haven't seen the video yet,
よかったら見てみてくださいね
please check it out!
ちょっと色々な思い出を作っていけたので
I made a lot of memories making it.
そして、いよいよですね
And now, the next song...
次の曲がラストになってしまいます
is going to be our last.
最後の曲は、せっかくなのであのステージで歌いたいと思います
Since it's the final song, let's sing it on that stage.
じゃあ移動しますのでちょっと待っててね
So, I'll be moving now, please wait a moment!
と いう わけ で やってきました! 水族館ステージ です! やーい!
So, here we are! Welcome to the 3D stage! Yay!
いや ちょっと ね 3D を お披露目 する 時 に この ステージ を 使っ た こと も あっ て
Now, I've used this stage once before when I first revealed my 3D model,
皆さん 思い出 が 深い ん じゃ ない か な と 思う の で この ステージ で 最後 は 曲 を 歌い たい と 思い ます｡
and I feel like it holds a lot of memories for everyone, so I wanted to sing my very last song here on this stage.
の 前 に ! の 前 に ! (笑)
Before that... Before that... (laughs)
あの です ね え この あと 22 時 30 分 から 坂間 が 作詞 作曲 し た オリ曲 の 『 光 あり 』 が プレミア 公開 に なり ます｡
Well, actually, starting at 10:30 PM tonight, Sakamata's original song "Hikari Ari" will premiere!
そちら も よかっ たら 見 て み て ください｡
I'd be so happy if you checked that out too!
この シークレット さん たち と 過ごし た 3 年 約 3 年間 の え 感謝 の 気持ち や 色々 な 思い を 込め て 作っ た の で 是非 見 て いただける と 嬉しい です｡
I made it filled with gratitude and various feelings from spending nearly three years with the Secret Society staff, so I'd be so glad if you watch it.
そして え ホロックス で の 歌 み た が なん と 23 時 頃 に 上がり ます の で そちら も よろしく お 願い いたし ます｡
And, HoloroX's song cover will also go up around 11:00 PM, so I hope you'll check that out too!
はい !
Yes!
で もう 1 個 ある ん です (笑)
And there's something else... (laughs)
これ の 話 じゃ なく て です ね ちょっと まあ ね 恥ずかしい ん です けど
This isn't about that, but... well, it's a bit embarrassing, but...
お ? えっ ?
Oh? Eh?
なに ? えっ ? えっ ? (笑)
What? Eh? Eh? (laughs)
ねえ やめ て よ そう いう の (笑)
Hey, stop it! Don't do that! (laughs)
サプライズ で マネ ちゃん から お 手紙 もらっ ちゃっ た !
Surprise! I actually got a letter from Manager-chan!
もう や だ よ ! ねえ !
No way! Stop it! (laughs)
泣か ない で き た じゃん ここ は ! ずるい よ ! (笑)
You shouldn't make me cry here! That's so mean! (laughs)
じゃあ ちょっと よ 読みたい と 思い ます｡
Well then, I guess I'll read it.
クロエ さん お疲れ様 です｡
"Chloe-san, thank you for your hard work.
少し 手際 少ない です が 初めて お 手紙 書い ちゃい ます ね｡
You might be a bit clumsy, but this is the first time you've written a letter, right?
まだまだ 未熟 な マネージャー の 私 に いつ でも 優しく 接し て くれ て ありがとう ござい まし た｡
Thank you so much for always being so gentle with an inexperienced manager like me.
いや もう こちら 本当に こちら こそ です けど ね 正直 楽しい こと ばかり で は なく 大変 な こと も たくさん あっ て どう し たら いい の か と 頭 を 悩まし た こと も あり まし た｡
To be honest, it really was just us two here... Honestly, it wasn't just fun things; there were many tough times, and I often worried about what I should do.
でも 黒江 さん と だ から 大変 な こと は 半分 に 楽しい こと は 倍 に この 3 年間 を 乗り切れ た と 思っ て ます｡
Even so, I feel like being with Chloe-san cut the hardships in half and doubled the fun, helping me get through these past three years.
気づい たら 家 の 中 が 黒江 さん の グッズ で いっぱい で
Before I knew it, my house was full of Chloe-san's merchandise,
仕事 に 行く とき は 娘 ちゃん が クロエ ちゃん に 会い に 行っ て くる の ? と 聞い て くる よう に なり まし た｡
and when I go to work, my daughter asks me, 'Are you going to go see Chloe-chan today?'
嬉しい 半面 今後 は なんて 答えれ ば いい の か 悩ん じゃい ます ね｡
I'm so happy about that, but I'm not sure how to answer from now on! (laughs)
この 3 年間 ダンス レッスン や ボイトレ 収録 など の お 仕事 を 真面目 に 一生 懸命 頑張っ て いる 姿 を 1番 近く で 見せ て いただき まし た｡
I've been watching you closely as you earnestly did your best with dance lessons, vocal training, and recording sessions over these past three years.
活動 に 関して あっち も 思い を 抱え てる 黒江 さん に 追いつこう と 必死 で 黒江 さん の 期待 に 応え られる よう 頑張っ て み た が 並ん で 仕事 が でき て い たり しよう か うーん｡
I tried my absolute best to support Chloe-san in her activities, hoping to live up to her expectations, but I wonder if I was able to be a proper manager for you?
あたりまえ ちゃん (笑) 当たり前 すぎる むしろ むしろ 助け られ て た みっ ちゃ 全然 全然 逆 だ けど な｡
It was only natural? No, rather, I was the one who was being helped so much; it was the exact opposite.
正直 とても 不安 でし た｡ 本当 は もっと もっと 色々 な こと を 教え て いただき たかっ た です｡
Honestly, I was very anxious. I honestly wish you could have taught me a lot more.
言葉 選び の センス シークレット さん と の 関わり 方 など 尊敬 しか ない けど 黒江 さん の マネージャー に なれ て 幸せ でし た｡
About word choice, my sense of taste, how to interact with Secret Society-san... I have nothing but respect for you, and I was so happy to be Chloe-san's manager.
記念 配信 で メイン さん と 堂々 と 立ち上げ てる 黒江 さん を 間近 で 見 させ て いただき その かっこいい 姿 忘れ ませ ん｡
Seeing you stand proudly with main-san at the anniversary stream made me forget how cool you looked, as I was right there up close.
本当 に お疲れ様 でし た｡ そして 見 た こと ない 景色 を たくさん 見せ て いただき ありがとう ござい まし た｡
You truly did a great job. And thank you for showing me so many sights I had never seen before.
これ から も 応援 し て ます マネ ちゃん より ね えっ !
I'll keep cheering you on from now on! More than Manager-chan, yeah? (laughs)"
いや さ 泣い ちゃう もう 本当 に もう やめ て よ って 思っ た のに さ P.S. 少女 P.S. 最後 の 最後 の 今日 も とても
I mean, you were crying so much, and I thought, "Stop crying!" but then... PS. "Chloe-chan, for this very last time, today is also very..."
大事なものを忘れてきて
I forgot important things,
妹ちゃんを召喚したのはいい思い出として大切に心にしまってあります。
and kept it close to my heart as a fond memory of summoning imouto-chan.
ふふっ(笑)
(Laughs)
これからもね お体にお気をつけてゆっくり休んで暮らせ おせ。ありがとー！
Please take care of yourself from now on. Arigato!
ふふっ(笑)
(Laughs)
すいません(笑)
毎回、毎回、毎回、本当に、本当いっぱいい教えてくれてるんですけどね、すぐ忘れちゃう。
They teach me so many things, but I always forget them.
いやもうね、ずるいよ。どうすんのここでさ、もう
I mean, how do you do it? Why am I crying here?
もう泣いちゃいそうだよ、もう。
I'm going to cry.
おもう。ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
ありがとうございました。本当に楽しかったです。
Thank you so much. It was really fun.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you.
ということで、えーサプライズすぎてわけわかんなかった。
And so...
もう、もうなんてこんなこれから歌うのにもやめてください、本当に。
Please stop making me cry before I even sing! Seriously.
(笑)
(Sighs)
ということで、えー、マリーちゃんからのサプライズのお手紙ありがとうございました。
So, Sekretto-san, thank you for the surprise letter!
坂田ま、シークレットさんに、お手紙帰ってきたんです！
Sakamata has received a letter from Sekretto-san!
読んでいいですか？(笑)
Should I read it?
読みます。
I'll read it.
シークレットさんへ、ホロライブでは短く、中学生が高校生になってしまうような、長いような、短いような、とても濃い時間を一緒に過ごしてくれて、ありがとうございました。
Dear Sekretto-san, during HoloLive, it feels like it was a short time, yet long—like a middle schooler turning into a high schooler. We spent a lot of intense time together. Thank you so much.
初配信ではぽんだらけでほぼアドリブで話していたり、ライブでも生歌に緊張しすぎて声が震えたり、よだれで溺れたり
During my first stream, I was all over the place and spoke almost entirely ad-lib. Even during lives, I was so nervous from singing live that my voice shook or I drowned in my own drool.
笑っちゃうようなことも、悔しいこともたくさんあったね。
There were things that made me laugh, and things that made me frustrated.
体を壊して心配をかけていくことが増えていき、坂田自身すごく悩んだし、申し訳なさから一人で泣いている時もありました。
I kept breaking my body and worrying more and more, and Sakamata herself was very troubled. There were times when I cried alone from sheer misery.
それでも、シークレットさんと過ごす日々のなかで、少しずつ成長していったり、自分を大切にしようという気持ちが強くなってきて、活動だけではなく、坂田の人生にとって大きな良い変化がたくさん起こりました。
Even so, through the days spent with Sekretto-san, I grew little by little, and my feeling of wanting to cherish myself grew stronger. Not just in activities, but it brought many major, positive changes to Sakamata's life.
それは偶然起きたものではなくて、シークレットさんがいつも優しく愛を届け続けてくれたから。この人たちにもっと笑っていてほしい、こんな素敵な人たちの大切なものである坂田が、坂田自身を大切にしなきゃだめだと思ったからだよ。
This wasn't something that just happened by chance. It's because Sekretto-san always gently continued to deliver love. That's why Sakamata thought that since Sekretto-san's precious people should smile more, Sakamata, who is precious to such wonderful people, must cherish herself too.
気づかせてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for making me notice that.
ホロライブで過ごして学んだことや思い出は、ずっと坂田の中に残ります。シークレットさんへの気持ちも、信頼も、絆も、何も変わることはありません。
The things I experienced and learned during HoloLive will stay in Sakamata's heart forever. My feelings, trust, and bond with Sekretto-san will never change.
大切にこの先も歩いていくので、この旅立ちを見守ってください。
I will keep walking forward carefully, so please keep watching over this journey.
本当に3年間ありがとうございました。大好きだよ！またどこかで。ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for the past three years. I love you so much! Thank you again, wherever we are.
はあー、もう気持ちぐちゃぐちゃ（笑）気持ちぐちゃぐちゃなのですが、
Phew, my feelings are a total mess right now... (Laughs)
次が本当に最後の曲です。みんな親ありがとうね。ありがとうございました。スタッフさんたちもありがとうございました。
Next is truly the final song. Everyone, thank you, and thank you so much, staff-san too.
それでは、聞いてください。「海の幽霊」
And now, please listen to "Ghost of the Sea."
開け放たれた この部屋には誰もいない
Open wide, this room is empty.
潮風の匂い 染み付いた椅子がひとつ
The scent of the ocean breeze, a single chair soaked through.
開け放された
Left wide open,
この部屋には誰もいない
there is no one in this room.
潮風の匂い
The scent of the sea breeze,
染み付いた椅子がひとつ
a single chair stained by it.
あなたが迷わないように 空けておくよ
I'll leave it open so you won't get lost.
軋む戸を叩いて
Knocking on the creaking door,
何から話せばいいのか
What should I even talk about first,
分からなくなる
until I don't even know anymore?
星が降る夜に あなたに会えた
In the night when stars fall, I met you.
あの夜を忘れはしない
I will never forget that night.
大切なことは 言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on a summer day,
思いがけず光るのは 海の幽霊
shining bright unexpectedly is a ghost of the sea.
うなだる夏の夕に
In the drooping summer evening,
桟橋を見送る
seeing off the pier.
いくつかの歌を唱う
humming several songs,
花を散らして
scattering flowers.
あなたがどこかで笑う声が聞こえる
I can hear your laughter somewhere,
熱い頬の手触り
the touch of your warm cheek.
ねじれた道を進んだら その瞬きが開く
If I walk down the twisted path, those blinking eyes will open.
離れ離れでもときめくものを
Even when separated, that fluttering thing—
叫ぼう 今は 幸せ と
I will shout out, "I am happy right now!"
大切なことは言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words,
踊る光に融かして
melting into the dancing light.
星が降る夜に あなたに会えた
In the night when stars fall, I met you.
あの夜を忘れはしない
I will never forget that night.
大切なことは言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on a summer day,
思いがけず光るのは 海の幽霊
shining bright unexpectedly is a ghost of the sea.
風薫る砂浜で また会いましょう
On the breeze-scented sandy beach, let's meet again.
離れ離れでも ときめくものを
Even when separated, that fluttering heart—
叫ぼう 今は 幸せ と
I will shout out, "I am happy right now!"
大切なことは 言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
跳ねる光に融かして
Melting into the bouncing light,
星が降る夜に あなたに会えた
in the night when stars fall, I met you.
あの夜を忘れはしない
I will never forget that night.
大切なことは 言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on a summer day,
思いがけず光るのは 海の幽霊
shining bright unexpectedly is a ghost of the sea.
離れ離れでも ときめくものを
Even when separated, that fluttering heart—
叫ぼう 今は 幸せ と
I will shout out, "I am happy right now!"
大切なことは 言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
跳ねる光に融かして
Melting into the bouncing light,
星が降る夜に あなたに会えた
in the night when stars fall, I met you.
あの夜を忘れはしない
I will never forget that night.
大切なことは 言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on a summer day,
思いがけず光るのは 海の幽霊
shining bright unexpectedly is a ghost of the sea.
風薫る 砂浜で また会いましょう
On the breeze-scented sandy beach, let's meet again.
お疲れ様です！
Good work!
お疲れ様でしたー！
Thanks for all your hard work!
お疲れ！良かったよ、
Great job! That was amazing,
沙花叉のライブ良かったー！歌上手いじゃん！
Sakamata's live was great! You're really good at singing!
今更？今更？ｗ
You're only saying that now?!
てかお腹空いたんですけど。
Man, I'm getting hungry.
あ、空いた！
Ah, me too!
お腹空いたね。
I'm hungry.
ルイ姉お腹空いてますよ！
Lui-ne, we're hungry!
今日夕飯、いや、今日はちょっと作りたくない！
Today's dinner... Well, today I don't feel like cooking!
ええー！？困るじゃん！だってってことは、お？
Whaaat?! That's a problem! Then does that mean...?
焼肉？
Yakiniku?
焼肉！焼肉！誰がお金出すの？
Yakiniku! Yakiniku! Who's paying for it?
焼肉！誰がお金出すの？焼肉！
Yakiniku! Who's paying? Yakiniku!
飯を食え！飯を食え！飯を食え！
Eat your rice! Eat your rice! Eat your rice!
焼肉！ざつ！肉！早く！
Yakiniku! Hurry up! Meat! Hurry!
いつもの焼肉行きましょうか。
Shall we go for our usual yakiniku?
行きが、行きが、そこで会おう。
Let's go, let's go, let's meet there.
いこいこそこ！いーっぱい踏んだ！いーっぱい踏んだ！ラプラス怒りね！
Let's go! We stepped on so much! Laplace is mad!
やだー！
No way!
あ、やば、財布忘れた。
Ah, crap, I forgot my wallet.
えっ！？は！？早く取ってきて！
Huh?! What?! Go grab it quickly!
財布、財布、財布じゃないよ！お前のお金持ってきてくれないよ！行ってくるね。
Wallet? Not my wallet—I mean, bring your own money! I'll be right back.
オッケー。
Okay.
待ってよー！
Wait up!
はやく！空いたよ、行くから待って！
Hurry! We're hungry, wait up!
早く！早く！焼肉！焼肉！焼肉！焼肉！焼肉！
Hurry! Hurry! Yakiniku! Yakiniku! Yakiniku! Yakiniku! Yakiniku!